Ben Charbonneau

Web Developer

(1) 608-630-3787

benscharb@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ben-charbonneau GitHub: github.com/BenCharbonneau Website: www.bencharbonneau.com

Summary

My first job out of was college was at a healthcare software company in customer service. While helping customers, I also got to do development to help meet their needs. It was while I did this work that I found my passion for development.

So I joined General Assembly's web development immersive program to hone my skills and prepare to join the world of professional developers. Going through the program has confirmed my passion, I find joy in perfecting the details of an application and the challenge of finding creative solutions to new problems. I'm excited to join the computer science community and make my mark on the world.

Experience

General Assembly (March 2018 - June 2018)

Student

- Created a ride sharing app called Carpoolic with one other developer. I owned the frontend code and she owned the backend code, which was broken off into an independent API, but we both did development on both sets of code. The frontend code was built using ReactJS and CSS. The backend API was built using Ruby and PostgreSQL for the database. The app allows users to coordinate carpools to events. Users can sign up and create rides to a specified destination as a driver or join rides as a passenger.
- Created a site for viewing AMC theatre showtimes with one other developer. The application uses the API endpoints that AMC has made available for viewing data on the movies showing in their theaters. I was primarily responsible for the API, search, and user authentication code and my partner was primarily responsible for presentation of the data and user workflows. The frontend was built with JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. The backend was built using Node.js and MongoDB for the database. Users can see the top 10 now showing movies and search for theaters, movies, and showtimes in their area. They can also save their search results to a wishlist.
- Created a co-operative monster shooting game. This was an independent project using JavaScript, HTML, HTML Canvas, and CSS. Players have to defeat waves of monsters together. The most exciting part is the AI for the zombies. They will chase the players around the map while staying clear of each other and obstacles.

Epic Systems (August 2014 – January 2018)

Technical Services Representative, MyChart Patient Portal

- Coded 40 different development projects in just over three years, while balancing day-to-day technical support for 11 hospital organizations, the most development projects for someone of my tenure in my application. These development projects both improved internal processes and troubleshooting and delivered critical enhancements to our organizations.
- Maintained a company-wide utility, accessible by over 8,000 employees and over 300 hospital organizations, that gathered and formatted data taken from customer environments and output it in Excel for reporting and analysis purposes.
- Branded 12 websites using HTML/CSS by updating logos, design, and wording to maintain each organization's branding within the framework of the website following each software upgrade.

Caché

Education Skills

Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology 2010-2014

Major: Bachelor of Science, Chemical Engineering

Minors: Material Science, Math, Spanish

JavaScript/jQuery Node.js noSQL SQL

HTML/CSS

ReactJS

Ruby

General Assembly March 2018-June 2018

Certificate: Web Development